

PROFILE

My primary strengths stem from Excel experience building accounting databases for a private real estate equity fund. Coding concepts and data science allow me to automate tasks and operate more efficiently. My interests are in transferring these Excel ETL processes into SQL databases to generate business intelligence insights, transforming data for sound ML analytics, and applying statistical approaches to illustrate solutions.

CONTACT

PHONE: 973-270-6473

WEBSITE:

www.github.com/gblack686

EMAIL:

Gblack686@gmail.com

HOBBIES

DataCamp
Dashboards
Real Estate Development
Bass Guitar
Live Music
Spanish
Chess
Continuous Learning

GREG BLACK

Data Science
Python Programming
Excel VBA Consulting
Business Intelligence Applications

EDUCATION

Pennsylvania State University – Smeal College of Business

Class of Spring 2015

Majored in Risk Management with a Real Estate Option. Cumulative GPA of 3.45. Independent study on CMBS modeling within Excel.

Data Analytics Bootcamp – University of California Irvine

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

Python - Jupyter, Pandas, SciPy, Selenium, Bokeh Data Viz, MRJob, PySpark, NLP Machine Learning – SKLearn, XGBoost, Exposure to Neural Networks SQL Experience – SQLite, PostgreSQL, projects querying and connecting to APIs Web Development – Django, Flask, HTML, Regex; exposure to JavaScript, D3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Econsult - Microsoft Excel VBA Consultant

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

Consulting, design and implementation for a financial analytics company in Santiago de Chile.

Developed models with VBA with interconnectivity between Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint to fully automate report templates.

Province West - Sales Broker Associate

Jun 2017 - Dec 2019

Developed Python scripts automating monthly reports and sales packages.

Consulted with institutional level executives on land acquisitions in the Inland Empire, gathering primary information and forecasting seasonal trends.

Underwrote land development proformas and generated competitive market analyses in support of the sale of \$45mm in transactions.

BKM Capital Partners – Private Equity Asset Management Analyst

Mar 2016 - Jun 2017

Redeveloped the quarterly valuation model and passed a PWC audit.

Automated a five-page institutional quality quarterly report.

Gained an understanding of the PE Fund operations including accounting practices, fund level waterfalls, acquisitions, and value-add development.

SKILLS

